+44 (0) 7446 782 228 mr.joseph.cai@gmail.com London NW2 LinkedIn Website @joseph-cai no-arbitrage.com

STATEMENT

With 6+ years in M&A and corporate development, I bring the rigour of a corporate finance professional and the insights of a data analyst—one by design, the other by discovery. Recognised for driving efficiency and progress, I go beyond execution to challenge assumptions, push bold ideas, and turn complexity into opportunity. I've transformed potential pitfalls into best practices, and now I'm seeking my next challenge. Let's connect!

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Crest Medical | Corporate Development (M&A) Manager/Director

Jan 2021 ~ Oct 2024 • Warrington / London

- Executed three transactions with a total deal value of £15m, including one divestiture and two acquisitions.
- Promoted to Corporate Development Director for distinct contributions, becoming the company's youngest director.
- Conducted comprehensive research over multiple synergistic industries of potential acquisitions.
- Upheld the company's standards for authoring high-impact memorandums and presentations for various stakeholders.
- Developed, maintained and presented advanced financial models using Excel and Power BI, providing clear insights that informed critical commercial decisions impacting c. £50 million annually.
- Established in-house BI reporting service; developed and maintained over 30 BI dashboards and automations, results
 include: 30% increased shelf availability, automated quotation process, and optimised pricing (c.10% margin increase).
- Appointed interim MD, leading post-merger integration and securing an exclusive partnership with a key national account.

Invenio Corporate Finance | Corporate Finance Sell-side M&A Associate

Aug 2017 ~ Aug 2020 • London

- Assisted senior partners in the origination and execution of mandates, including 10+ lower-mid market sell-side mandates with a total value of £160m+ in diverse sectors (Consumer, Healthcare, Service and TMT).
- Promoted from Analyst Intern to Associate in 14 months for outstanding work quality and contributions to the team.
- Financial Modelling: served as the primary modeller supporting the VP, taking a leading role in building, refining and maintaining transaction models (Operating Model, DCF, LBO, M&A).
- Client Interaction: Acted as point of contact for clients, praised by partners for building trusted client-advisor relationships.
- Document Preparation: authored CIM and teasers including conducting industry and company research, presenting final
 work in consulting style, Clients often requested me as the lead author, with some even specifying it in engagement letters.
- Managed Due Diligence: administrating virtual data rooms coordinated virtual data rooms, handled Q&A with buyers and sellers, and worked alongside accountants and legal teams to drive the process forward.
- Mentorship: Supervised junior analysts and delivered advanced modelling training sessions.

Boston Consulting Group | Part-time Assistant (Intern)

Jan 2016 ~ Aug 2016 • Beijing

- Supported a FinTech project pitch by conducting preliminary research on a major Chinese e-commerce company.
- Applied hypothesis-driven methodologies in a benchmarking project against TSMC for Samsung.
- Documented 50+ industry expert interviews, earning commendations from senior consultants for their depth and accuracy.

EDUCATION

Imperial College London, Business School

2016 ~ 2017

MSc Finance & Accounting with Distinction (GPA 83/100); Recognised in Dean's List for Academic Excellence

Core Modules: Financial Accounting Mergers & Acquisitions
 Private Equity & Venture Capital Derivative Investment & Portfolio Mgt.

Structured Credit & Equity Products Advanced Corporate Finance

University of International Business and Economics (China)

2012 ~ 2016

Bachelor of Economics, Major in Finance; First-class equivalent (GPA 90/100)

SKILLS & STRENGTHS

- Financial Statement Analysis & Valuation
- Advanced Financial Modelling with Excel
- Expert in Microsoft Office Suite
- Excellent numerical and quantitative skills

- Programming skills (SQL, Python, MATLAB, Typescript)
- Advanced data skills (PowerPivot, Power Bl, M)
- Project management and stakeholder management
- English, Mandarin

INTERESTS & OTHER

Interests Tech enthusiast; Coding hobbyist; Guzheng Instrumentalist (professionally certified); Roller-skating.

Volunteering Member of CFA UK Social Committee; Fundraise coach for social impact start-ups/projects on MovingWorlds.